

Professional Summary

Gururaja Murthy

Profile: Project Manager / Agile Scrum Master/QA Leader

An Experienced and Certified IT Professional with extensive 18+ years of experience in Product/Project Management, Agile Scrum Master ,QA Test Management , Defect Management, Release Management, People Management , Outsource management and Client Management in Multi-Million Dollar Software Development Applications for Industries as Banking Financial Insurance Mortgage, Health Care & Life Science Management, Security, ERP, Airline, Logistics Telecom , Supply chain Management, Manufacturing, Automobiles, Manufacturing and Retail/E- Commerce.

Education and Credentials

- Master's in Computer Application First Class
- Project Management Certification Kent State University (PMP)
- Certified Scrum Master from Scum Alliance CSM
- Certified Product Owner -CSPO

Core Competency	Technical Skill set
Specialized Technology	Mobility, Digital, SOA/Web services, IOS, Android, Mongo DB, Cloud-
	HP/VMware, and Data Analytics.
Software Development	Java, J2ee, EJB, JSP, HTML, CSS, Java script, XML, Microsoft Dot Net,
technology	Angular JS, Android SDK and IOS
Database/ Big Data	Oracle, DB2, SQL Server, Mongo DB.
Functional Areas	Digital, Client Server Applications, Web Applications, Mainframes,
	Mobility, Cloud Platform.
Enterprise System/Business	Actuate(BIRT), Cognos and SSRS
Intelligence	
Data warehouse/Analytics	Microsoft Integration services (DTS and SSIS), Informatica, Data
	Stage .
Sustained engineering or	Hot fix, Patch, Upgrade, compatibility, Regression, Release and
Critical engineering services	Deployment
Test Management	HP ALM, Rational Test Manager, IBM Test Management Tool,
	Microsoft Test Manager
Test Automation and CI/CD	Rational Suite Enterprise, HPUFT, Load Runner 9.0, BPT, Selenium and
	Ranorex, Jira, Jenkins
Defect Management system	Rational Clear Quest, PVCS Tracker, Test Director, JIRA, Mantis and
	TFS
SQA	Reviews, Internal Audits, Process Health check
	(CMMi- level 5)
Process	Agile, Kanban, RUP, V-Model
Performance testing	Load runner, Rational performance tester, Apache-JMeter

SOA track	SOAP UI, REST services, ITKO LISA
Infrastructure Track	IBM Appscan, Vmware, Clustered apps
Airline Track	Ticketing system, Inflight Exchange.
Healthcare package	Medco express scripts
Telecom Track	Billing packages from BT and AT&T
logistics Track	FedEx ship manager
Security Track	IBM Appscan, VMware, Clustered testing
Oracle packages track	Siebel CRM 8.0, People soft HRMS
SAP packages track	SAP SD and CRM
Business process	PEGA PRPC
management	
Sales force packages track	Sales force CRM
Configuration	Rational Clear Case, Visual Source Safe, PVCS Dimension.
Management /Release	
Management	
Mobile Application	Android, IOS, Blackberry, Windows phone OS
Development	

Key IT Projects/Solutions Delivered for Global Fortune Customers – U.S.A, U.K, Canada, Germany, France, Australia Singapore, South Africa and Malaysia.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Project Experience Highlights:

MINDTREE Limited – Project -Test Manager/Scrum Master

Feb 2016-Present (USA)

Client Name : Fortune listed BFSI client – North Carolina

Description : Life, RPS and Annuity Insurance applications (IOS, Android, Web Platform)

- Responsible for Creation of the Project plan and Test plan
- Responsible for People Management; Responsible Scheduling, Tracking and Reporting;
- Responsible for Resource allocation (people, hardware, software, and facilities);
- Responsible for Metric Preparation and Reporting;
- Responsible for Managing, supervising, and assessing team performance
- Responsible for Defining project scope, goals and
- Deliverables that support business goals in collaboration with senior management and stakeholders;
- Responsible for Liaising with project stakeholders on an ongoing basis & ensuring Customer Satisfaction;
- Responsible for reports publishing with upward management
- Agile Project Track: Helping team regarding Grooming of user stories and Estimation (JIRA, Scrumwise, Confluence).

- Use Product Backlog and come up with a release plan & Sprint plan during Sprint 0.
- Sprint Planning and Story Point decision using pocker card with the agile team.
- Daily Scrum call/Stand-ups with the Agile team to identify any blocker/impediment.
- Resolve Blocker/issues immediately collaborating with required interface team/stakeholders.
- Continuous Integration and Delivery: DevOPS, Automation testing. Daily status updates.
- Sprint Review at the last day of the sprint with the PO to demo the shipped product.
- Conduct Sprint Retrospective post the completion of the sprint. Come up with action items.
- Effectively use of Collaborative tools and JIRA/Confluence tool for Agile process, time tracking, metrics.

Mphasis Limited- An HP Company: Agile Scrum Master | Project Manager | QA-Test Manager. March 2010-Feb 2016 (U.S.A. and Bangalore)

Project Name : Sigma BI for AIG

Technology : IOS and Android Apps, Business analytics-IBM Data Stage, DB2, Informatica,

Cognos Reports, Adobe CQ5, IOS and Android app.

Project Name : American Airlines SABRE- Trip case;
Role : Project Manager /Scrum Master

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment: Software Development Track

- Sprint Release planning, Daily Standup meeting, Problem solutions, Sprint Demo and Retrospective
- Facilitating Scrum of Scrum for offshore Scrum teams in US and India
- Managing the overall performance and delivery of cross-functional
- Facilitating sprint planning as Scrum master for multiple Scrum teams
- Publicizing the team's progress and successes to make sure they are highly visible
- To product owner's/ stakeholders. Ensuring the team together till the release completion
- Ensuring the transition of Projects from Waterfall to Agile

Maintenance Projects/Testing Projects Track

- Responsible for Creation of Project plan and the Test plan
- Responsible for People Management; Responsible Scheduling, Tracking and Reporting
- Responsible for Resource allocation (people, hardware, software, and facilities)
- Responsible for Metric Preparation and Reporting;
- Responsible for Managing, supervising, and assessing team performance
- Responsible for Defining project scope, goals and Deliverables that support business goals in collaboration with senior management and stakeholders
- Responsible for Liaising with project stakeholders on an ongoing basis & ensuring Customer Satisfaction
- Responsible for automation using Ranorex version 5.0
- Responsible for Set up and manage project expectations with team members and other stakeholders
- Hiring and retaining talent into the organization and projects;

- Responsible for Coaching, mentor, motivate and supervise Project team members and influence them to take positive action and accountability for their assigned work
- Develop and deliver progress reports, proposals, requirements documentation and presentations
- Responsible for proactively managing changes in project scope
- Identify potential crises and devise contingency plans
- Responsible for Defining project success criteria and disseminate them to involved parties throughout Project life cycle and Delivery

Project Name : Schwab Index Advantage for Charles Schwab Corporation

Technology : Microsoft team foundation server; Microsoft Integration services, Microsoft

reporting services; Actuate Reporting system, Cloud computing Platform.

Role : Test Manager/Leader

Description : Schwab Retirement planning application

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment

Reaching agreement with client about the assignment and expectations

- Ensuring test infrastructure is available on time
- Keeping the issue administration continually updated
- Responsible for end to end delivery from offshore team.
- Responsible for planning, execution and reporting of test
- Conducted Security testing & Performance testing.

Project Name : CAFÉ – Customer Automation for Future Endeavour for FedEx

Technology : HP ALM, Business process testing, quick Test Pro

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment

- Responsible for the team of 30 testing resources
- Responsible End to end testing delivery to the customer
- Responsible for the team appraisals
- Responsible for defect analysis and management
- Responsible for the process management
- Responsible for the customer management
- Responsible for both offshore delivery teams in Bangalore and Mangalore

Marlabs Software (P) Ltd - Project Leader /Release Manager (Aug 2008 – March 2010)

Project Name : In-Flight Exchange (IFX4) ™ Product suite = Supply chain management

for Air line services for gate gourmet Customers

Technology : SAP R/34.0, SAP Test Acceleration and Optimization, Quality center, Loadrunner

Client : Gate Gourmet Inc. U.S.A

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment:

- Responsible for application test management for multiple projects
- Managed team of 18-20 testers
- Responsible for Estimation and Risk Management
- Interaction with customer on daily basis
- Coordinated with automation team for testing using QTP
- Coordinated with performance test team using Load Runner
- Reported QA team status to executives
- Managed defects using Jira
- SPOC for testing during testing QA, UAT and Production environment.
- Standardize QA standards and practices for the project teams
- Coordinated for tool evaluation and POC (Proof of Concept)
- Collection of Metrics and Reporting to the Management.
- Working closely with Business development team to articulate Business value through Testing solutions and help them to close new accounts (Proposals and SOW's)

Tratum Technologies Pvt. Ltd - QC lead (Dec 2007 – Jul 2008)

Project Name : Prepaid and Post-Paid Billing Systems for British Telecom

Client : British Telecom - U.K.

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment:

- Day to day test management, reporting and defect management
- Prepared status reports for management and drafted Test Completion Report.
- Member of SEPG
- Ensuring a test infrastructure is available on time.
- Allowing use of all agreed test methodologies
- Support in the Test project proposal creation, Sow's and roadmap for transition
- Coordination and participation in the client application portfolio assessment & estimation
- Managed, planned and allocated test resources for projects.

Mphasis – An EDS Company - Test Lead (Jan 2006 – Jul 2007)

Project : CRM package

Client : Charles Schwab financial corporation

Duration : 01/2006 - 12/2006

Project : Auto-write off
Client : **Xerox Corporation**Duration : 01/2007 - 07/2007

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment:

Process Improvement

- Prepared requirement clarification tracker to manage requirements.
- Authored gap analysis tracker to manage gap between wire frames
 And functional specifications.
- Authored release management process for testing team.
- Wrote and maintained Master test plan, Estimations, risks, issues, templates, Review Reports and Test Reports.
- Ensuring adherence to software quality process

Test Management

- Test planning, scheduling and monitoring
- Test estimation using industry standard estimation models.
- Resource recruitment and management
- Single point of contact for testing teams both at Bangalore and Chennai.
- The team establishes testing processes, testing standards, test case designs, defects, and reviews, test reports.
- Migrated several applications from onsite to offshore.
- Managed all types of testing such as Functional, System, Reliability, Performance, Load, Usability, Security, Compatibility, Acceptance, Regression using Manual and Automation Techniques
- Responsible for Defect Tracking and Defect Management.

Client Management

- Regular communication with customers
- Relationship management.
- Reporting the QA status to onsite executives on regular basis
- Providing solutions
- Publish software test deliverables identified during each control point of SDLC, including Test plan, Test cases, Defect and Test reports.
- Support in Test project proposal creation and roadmap for transition

•

People Management

- Control and Monitor the team by giving specified inputs
- Encourage team members to attend training program at least once in 3 months
- Responsible for team members appraisals
- Started new initiatives like celebrating team members marriage anniversaries and birthdays
- Interacting with each team member and prepare growth plan

Contribution to the organization

- Submitted Test management white papers
- Submitted QA handbook to organization
- Member of Testing Competency Interviewer's panel.
- Authored testing process for onsite-offshore delivery model.

Commerce Velocity (India) Pvt. Ltd - Test Lead

(Aug 2005 – Jan 2006)

Project Name : Credit Quality Decision Suite this is an integrated solution for Mortgage banking
Client : Mylor financial services, Funding America Wilmington financial services, Bear

Stearns, Green light, NRT, Zero Down Mortgage, AHL, FNLC, VERITAS, Option One.

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment:

- Managing Multiple leading clients such as Mylor financial services, Funding America
 Wilmington financial services, Bear Stearns, Green light, NRT, Zero Down Mortgage, AHL, FNLC, VERITAS, Option One.
- Leading a team of 10 resources.
- Managed creation of process for testing
- People management and test management, resource allocation & planning.
- Value add: Test repository creation and management
- Values add: Provide training guidance and growth opportunities for growing staff.
- Values add: improved communication between QA and Dev team.
- Author Release Notes for each deployment of software.
- Provide test results to be used by management as criteria for migration into Production environment(s).
- Test planning and tracking and monitoring.
- Co-coordinating with onsite/client
- Handles all critical issues and reviews with QA Analyst

IBM GLOBAL SERVICES PVT. LTD - Test lead (Jul 2004 – Aug 2005)

Project Name : PBM – Pharmaceutical Benefit Management system for Merck fortune

pharmaceutical company

Client : Merck & Co., Inc

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment:

- Leading team of 9-11 QA test engineers.
- Report QA team status to Onsite Executives
- Responsible for Test data creation
- Responsible for multiple applications on Mainframe and Web.
- Development of testing strategy and work assignments among team members.
- Designing of test plans, test cases, reports and its maintenance using Test Management Tool (TMT tool)
- Designing of various templates according to customer specifications
- Responsible for Performance appraisal to team members
- Training the testing team before putting them on production on testing methodologies.
- Hiring resources. Member of the project recruitment team for testing resources.
- Interviewing and scheduling the client interview and member of IBM testing Competency Interviewer's panel.
- Mentored team members in use of Merant PVCS tracker for Defect tracking
- Develop documentation in PPS and Excel to track deliverables

- Interviewed all QA resources and recommended to Dept. Manager and testing Competency R.D.M on hiring.
- Defect tracking and Reporting found for developers using Merant PVCS Tracker
- Signing off the Quality Gates (Delivery to the customer)

Microcon International Ltd – Senior Test Engineer (Feb 2002 - Jun 2004)

Project Name : HMS version 1.0

Hospital Management system;

Client : Parkway Group

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment:

- Supervise 4-5 test engineers ensuring proper testing and regression testing was achieved
- Deliverables included Test Plan, Test cases execution reports, Defect reports
- Mentored team members in use of Multi-site Rational Clear Quest for Defect Tracking.
- Monitor schedules
- Lead the Quality Review Process Group within the Team
- Knowledge Transfer to new hired employees to assume QA roles.
- Maintained project statistics, such as defect rate and severity, milestones met.
- Implement Automated Testing Methodology and best practices for QA Team Using Rational Testing suites.
- Developed Modularized Rational Robot automated test scripts for Web and
- Client/Server Applications
- Aid in design and implementation of Load Testing using Rational Load test.
- Utilize Clear Quest for Manual and Automated defect tracking, and Reporting.
- Ensure defects of unit testing and integration testing been closed before Carrying out system testing.

ADS Technologies Pvt. Ltd – Test Engineer (Sep 98 – Dec 2001)

Product : IBS Versions 1.2 and 1.2

Technology : Integrated Business solution – End to end ERP solutions for Retail Industries.

Roles and Responsibilities Accomplishment:

- Manual testing. Prepared test cases and test data generation
- System testing and functional testing, Usability testing.
- Bugs found in the Application were entered in Spreadsheet.
- Filing of System test error logs and defining error priorities in test error reports.
- Executed, analyzed and evaluated test results, conducted validation and verification of Software